(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
周防パトラ 誕生3Dライブ 2025
重大発表あり！ 3D新髪型お披露目
Suou Patra Birthday 3D Live 2025
Major Announcement! 3D New Hairstyle Reveal
５、４、３、２、１！
5, 4, 3, 2, 1!
Are you ready?
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra!
パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！
Patra! Patra! Patra! Patra!
Here we go!
Ready?
1, 2, 3, 4!
Happy Happy Birthday 今日は最高な記念日
Happy Happy Birthday! Today is the best anniversary!
君と一緒に笑い合おう 準備はいいかな？
Let's laugh together! Are you ready?
パパパパトラと踊り明かそう
Let's dance all night with Pa-pa-pa-Patra!
キラキラ輝く世界へ 行こう！
Let's go to a sparkling world!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra!
パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！
Patra! Patra! Patra! Patra!
Alright!
ドキドキしちゃうよ 視線感じて
My heart is racing, feeling your gaze
ドレスに着替えて 魔法をかけて
Change into a dress and cast a spell
尻尾をフリフリ リズムに乗れば
Wiggle my tail and get into the rhythm
みんなのハートを 奪っちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna steal everyone's hearts!
ワン！ツー！ワンツー！スリー！
One! Two! One-two! Three!
甘い声で 囁くよ
I'll whisper with a sweet voice
耳元で 好きって言っちゃうかも？
I might even say "I love you" in your ear.
照れちゃうけど 本気なんだから
I'm shy, but I'm serious
ちゃんと見ててね 私のこと
Make sure you look at me
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra!
パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！
Patra! Patra! Patra! Patra!
いくよー！
Here we go!
Happy Happy Birthday 今日は最高な記念日
Happy Happy Birthday! Today is the best anniversary!
君と一緒に笑い合おう 準備はいいかな？
Let's laugh together! Are you ready?
パパパパトラと踊り明かそう
Let's dance all night with Pa-pa-pa-Patra!
キラキラ輝く世界へ 行こう！
Let's go to a sparkling world!
ずっとずっと忘れないよ 今日という日を
I'll never, ever forget this day
君に出会えて 幸せだよ
I'm so happy I met you
これからもずっと よろしくね
I look forward to being with you from now on too
最高の誕生日にしよう！
Let's make this the best birthday ever!
Yeah!
５、４、３、２、１！
5, 4, 3, 2, 1!
Are you ready?
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra!
パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！
Patra! Patra! Patra! Patra!
Here we go!
Ready?
1, 2, 3, 4!
Happy Happy Birthday 今日は最高な記念日
Happy Happy Birthday! Today is the best anniversary!
君と一緒に笑い合おう 準備はいいかな？
Let's laugh together! Are you ready?
パパパパトラと踊り明かそう
Let's dance all night with Pa-pa-pa-Patra!
キラキラ輝く世界へ 行こう！
Let's go to a sparkling world!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra! Go Patra!
パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！パトラ！
Patra! Patra! Patra! Patra!
Alright!
ドキドキしちゃうよ 視線感じて
My heart is racing, feeling your gaze
ドレスに着替えて 魔法をかけて
Change into a dress and cast a spell
尻尾をフリフリ リズムに乗れば
Wiggle my tail and get into the rhythm
翔べ！ガンダム
Fly! Gundam
燃え上がれ 燃え上がれ
Burn up, burn up
燃え上がれ ガンダム
Burn up, Gundam
君よ
You...
走れ
Run!
まだ 怒りに 燃える 闘志があるなら
If you still have the fighting spirit burning with anger
巨大な 敵を 撃てよ 撃てよ 撃てよ
Shoot the giant enemy, shoot, shoot, shoot!
正義の 怒りを ぶつけろ ガンダム
Unleash your righteous anger, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam, Gundam!
立ち上がれ 立ち上がれ 立ち上がれ ガンダム
Stand up, stand up, stand up, Gundam!
君よ
You...
叫べ
Cry out!
まだ 絶望に 沈む 悲しみあるなら
If you still have sorrow sinking in despair
恐怖を 払って 行けよ 行けよ 行けよ
Shake off the fear and go, go, go!
渦巻く 血潮を 燃やせ ガンダム
Burn the swirling blood, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam, Gundam!
皆様！
Everyone!
周防パトラ生誕祭 お越しいただいてどうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Suou Patra's Birthday Celebration!
パトラ行きます！
Patra, heading out!
蘇る 蘇る 蘇る ガンダム
Revive, revive, revive, Gundam!
君よ
You...
掴め
Seize it!
まだ 愛に ふるえる 心があるなら
If you still have a heart trembling with love
平和を 求めて 飛べよ 飛べよ 飛べよ
Fly in search of peace, fly, fly, fly!
銀河へ 向かって 飛べよ ガンダム
Fly towards the galaxy, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam, Gundam!
魂が奮い立つような この力。
This power that makes my soul tremble.
次々に蘇る 歴戦の記憶。
Memories of past battles revive one after another.
これは、先達たちの…
This is from my predecessors...
今、受け継ごう。
Now, I shall inherit them.
歴代のパトラの 力と記憶を！
The power and memories of all past Patras!
はい！ということで、最終形態、周防パトラですわー！
Yes! And so, this is the final form, Suou Patra!
今回も、豪華ステージ、そして新衣装！
Once again, a gorgeous stage and a new outfit!
さらに巨大カニタマもいるよー！ということで
Plus, there's a giant Kanitama too!
よっしゃー！
Alright!
改めまして、こんばんわーわー！
Once again, good evening-evening!
そう、パトラ生誕祭お越しいただきありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you for coming to Patra's Birthday Festival!
はい、見てください。まずは新衣装！気になってる方も多いと思うんですけど...
Yes, look! First is the new outfit! I'm sure many of you were curious about it...
あ、椅子のほうが気になりますが、これロマンシング・サガ2です。はい！
Ah, you might be curious about the chair, but this is from Romancing SaGa 2. Yes!
はい、じゃあ下からね。
Okay, let's start from the bottom.
なんと！はい、靴。ちゃんと今回も新衣装なんですけど...
Look! Yes, the shoes. These are also part of the new outfit...
あの、あちら、ヒールがあります。
Well, over there, they have heels.
間違えた。ヒールがあります。
Wait, I misspoke. There are heels.
そして、このベルトも可愛いでしょ？はい。
And this belt is cute too, right? Yes.
で、今回は鉄壁のスカートになっております。
And this time, it's an ironclad skirt.
結構ね、動いても、はい、鉄壁で頑丈になっております。
Even if I move a lot, yes, it remains ironclad and sturdy.
それから、おへそ！見て見て見て、セクシーでしょ？
And then, the belly button! Look, look, look, it's sexy, right?
そして、ベルトもね、かっちりになっております。
And the belt is also tightly fastened.
白衣装のときよりちょっと抑えられてるんで、揺れが、あの、ちょっと足りないかもしれないんですけど...
It's a bit more contained than in the white outfit, so the movement might be slightly less, but...
今回もボインボインでお送りいたします。
I'll still be presenting it with plenty of bounce.
そしてそして！じゃーん！ポニーテール！新髪型になっております。
And, and! Ta-da! A ponytail! It's a new hairstyle.
ハートのね、アクセサリーが揺れて可愛いでしょ、これも。
The heart accessory sways and is cute, right? This one too.
ほれほれほれ。
Look, look, look.
あー、という感じでね、とっても可愛い新衣装になりました。
Ah—and so, it's become a very cute new outfit.
さらにみんなが気になってると思うんですけど、はい！
And I'm sure there's something else everyone's curious about... yes!
パッ！なんと脱げまーす！
Poof! I can actually take it off!
え、これYouTube的に大丈夫かな？まあ大丈夫かな。見て見て見て見て。
Wait, is this okay for YouTube? Well, probably. Look, look, look, look.
こうね、ハートのくり抜きがあるんですよ。
See, there's a heart-shaped cutout here.
背中の筋がまたセクシーですね。
The definition of the back is also quite sexy.
あ、そうそう、今回もね、ちゃんと、はい、脇が丸見えになっております。
Ah, yes, and this time too, the armpits are fully visible.
たくさんたくさんスクショ待ってます。
I'm looking forward to lots and lots of screenshots.
はい、ということで、ハッシュタグ「周防パトラ生誕祭」でよろしくお願いします。
So, please use the hashtag "Suou Patra Birthday Festival."
感想とかね、あの、コメント待ってるよ。
I'm waiting for your thoughts and comments.
お、可愛いコメントいっぱいありがとう！
Oh, thank you for all the cute comments!
はー、いっぱいね、撮ってくださいね。
Wow, please take lots of photos.
ふっ、ふん、ふん、ふん、あの、なんかセクシーな恰好はどうやればいいのか分からないんだけど...
Phew, hmmm... I don't really know how to strike a sexy pose, but...
皆さんのスクショテクにお任せします！
I'll leave it to your screenshot skills!
じゃ、早速次の曲行きたいと思います！
Well then, let's head straight to the next song!
悩める人への口上
A speech to those who suffer
止まらずの盲女
A blind girl who doesn't stop
名も無き目の地上の
On the earth with nameless eyes
行き届いている惨め
The misery that is everywhere
襲い出した過去も
The past that has begun to haunt
退屈な未来も
The boring future too
カウンセリング、ヤニ、嫌で
Counseling, nicotine, I hate it
虚言とダイ・ピ・ピ・ピ
Lies and die-pi-pi-pi
A happy, A lucky
Be happy, UNDEAD
ねぇねぇねぇ、なんだかどうして戦っているようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, for some reason I feel like I'm fighting
振り切れないこれだったな
It was this that I couldn't shake off
過去の自分、自分、自分、自分、自分
My past self, self, self, self, self
とっくに死んでる透明な防護ターゲット
A transparent protective target that died long ago
痛いけれど痛いけれど記憶の奥底
It hurts, it hurts, deep in my memories
もういないのにあっちがいいアイロニー
The irony that that's better even though it's gone
使い古されているのは今の自分ナンセンス
It's nonsense that my current self is worn out
消えない劣等、イエス、弱コンプレックス
Ineffaceable inferiority, yes, a weak complex
取り憑かれているみたい巻き付いたまま
Like being possessed, remaining entwined
まだ放してない慈悲の自分
My merciful self that hasn't let go yet
UNDEAD 真理じゃないオールナイトマイの泥酔
UNDEAD, not the truth, but an all-night-my drunken stupor
生きてる事とは変わり続ける事だろう
Living probably means continuing to change
不公平に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be satisfied with resigning to unfairness
幸せになろうとしないなんて拒絶
Rejecting the idea of not trying to be happy
この世この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a strange, strange fantasy
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake appear next?
当てて当てて八度始まる物語
Guess, guess, the story that begins for the eighth time
人か化け物か可愛いダイ・ピ・ピ・ピ
A human or a monster? A cute die-pi-pi-pi
バー
Ba-
なんだかどうして未来になんぞなるの
Why and how does it become the future?
拷問的、楽観的なような気がして
Feeling like something torturous yet optimistic
随分生きてる既視感とテンプレ食傷
A sense of déjà vu and being fed up with templates from living too long
出来な出来事の気配もない
Not even a sign of an event that could happen
積んだ経験の因果経過が壊された神話は退屈な進化
A myth where the causality of accumulated experience is destroyed is a boring evolution
刺激が欲しいんだ、おっちょこちょいになっちゃった
I want stimulation, I've become a scatterbrain
完成、整っていくカオス、増えるコンプライアンス
Completion, chaos getting organized, increasing compliance
腐らされていくみたい数珠繋ぎして
Like being made to rot, linked together like beads
あれもこれもどれも同じ
This and that, everything is the same
熱い熱い熱い！
Hot, hot, hot!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
信じられない
Unbelievable
Oh, might might my no 連鎖
Oh, might might my chain
いつの世も過去も未来も今にあるんだ
Every era, the past, and the future, they're all in the now.
生きていることを愚直に果たそうよ
Let's straightforwardly fulfill the act of living.
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
信じられない Oh, might に言ってるんだ
Unbelievable, going to Oh might.
幸せを閃いてしまわぬ人であれ
Be someone who never stops flashing with happiness.
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ 死んでるも同然
Just getting used to and enduring pain is the same as being dead.
屍のあけた！
The carcass opened it!
悩み疲れたのなら今日ならずとも明日
If you're tired of worrying, if not today, then tomorrow.
絶やさず目指せよ 生きているんだから
Keep aiming without fail, because you're alive.
不幸に浸るもん 幸せになるもん 全部全部お前だ
Indulging in misfortune, becoming happy, it's all up to you.
ここにいたいから 信じる場所 ピースピースピース
Because I want to be here, the place I believe in. Peace peace peace!
パ！エブリワン ジャンプインザパ
Pa! Everyone jump in the Pa!
パ！エブリワン ラブインザパ
Pa! Everyone love in the Pa!
ヒトならぬところ いつも通りかと 生き抜くこの化け物ばかりの物語
In a non-human place, just like always, surviving this story full of monsters.
ちゃっかりしっかり、誕生グッズのお知らせだよ！
I'm here to properly announce my birthday goods!
なんと！パトラの、て...
Unbelievable! Patra's...
かわいいマウスパッドや、バスタオル！
...cute mousepad and bath towel!
そしてとってもかわいいアクリルスタンド、A4サイズのファイル！
And a very cute acrylic stand, and an A4 size file!
いろんなグッズがある誕生日グッズが登場だよ！
All sorts of items are now available as birthday goods!
受注生産なので、売り切れの心配なし！
They're made to order, so no need to worry about them selling out!
8月30日までの受付です！よろしくお願いします！
Orders are open until August 30th! Thank you!
FINAL FANTASY V ビッグブリッヂの死闘
FINAL FANTASY V: Battle on the Big Bridge
UNDERTALE Megalovania
ロマンシング サ・ガ2 七英雄バトル
Romancing SaGa 2: Seven Heroes Battle
アーマード・コア4 Panther
Armored Core 4: Panther
仮面ライダー サモンライド! Break The World
Kamen Rider SummonRide!: Break The World
放たれた 矢が的へ向かうように
Like an arrow shot towards its target
自らの 気持ちも向き合いつつ
While facing my own feelings
理由など そこに宿命あった
Without reason, destiny was there
ただ進む 仲間と共にゆく
Simply moving forward with my comrades
気持ちは一つ 水面に映る君は
Our hearts are one, you reflected on the water's surface
...いたゲート見つめている
...staring at the gate.
果てしなく続く
Continuing endlessly...
歪んだワールド突き進む
Pushing through this distorted world.
強い意志で限界を打ち破れ
Break through the limits with a strong will.
君は侍！
You are a Samurai!
時を導け 侍！
Lead the time, Samurai!
意志を宿し
Harbor your will...
願いを一つに集め
...and gather your wishes into one.
全てを超えて突き抜けろ
Surpass everything and break through.
侍！ 空へと放つ
Samurai! Launch toward the sky.
侍！ ここに舞い
Samurai! Dance here.
灼熱の地へ
To the scorching land...
駆け抜けろ
...run through!
君は侍！ 時を超えて
You are a Samurai! Beyond time.
侍！ 祈り届け
Samurai! Deliver your prayer.
想いを絆に変えて
Turn your feelings into bonds.
一点突破突き抜けろ
Break through everything at a single point!
侍！ 次元を超え
Samurai! Beyond dimensions.
侍！ 全ては今
Samurai! Everything is now.
灼熱の地へ
To the scorching land...
駆け抜けろ
...run through!
はい、ということで聴いてくれてありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you so much for listening!
今何をやってるかと言うと
As for what I'm doing right now...
とってもこの後可愛いゲストが来るので
A very cute guest is coming on next,
フェロモン出し捲っていました。はぁ～
so I've been giving off pheromones like crazy. *Sigh*
なんかドキドキするな。
I'm so nervous.
それでは呼びたいと思います。
Well then, I'd like to call them out.
本日のスペシャルゲスト、おいでー！
Today's special guests, come on out!
おはよー！バウバウ、パトラ様！
Oha-you! Bau bau, Patra-sama!
ハッピーバースデー！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう、バウバウ。
Thank you, bau bau!
にゃ～、FUWAMOCOちゃんの二人に来てもらいました！
Nyah! We have the FUWAMOCO duo here with us!
じゃ、自己紹介お願いします。
Please introduce yourselves.
はい、チワワじゃないよ、フワワだよ！
Yes! I'm not a Chihuahua, I'm Fuwawa!
フワワじゃないよ、モココだよ！
I'm not Fuwawa, I'm Mococo!
Hololive English -Advent-の魔界の番犬シスターズ
The demon guard dog sisters from Hololive English -Advent-,
二人合わせて、FUWAMOCOです！
together, we are FUWAMOCO!
バウバウ！
Bau bau!
はぁ～、バウバウ様～、はぁ～、パトラ様～
Haa~ Bau-bau-sama~, Haa~ Patra-sama~
はぁ～、ありがたいです。
Haa~ I'm so grateful.
いや、FUWAMOCOちゃんはパトラがね
Well, for FUWAMOCO-chan, I...
ASMRボイスをプロデュースして
produced their ASMR voices.
ね、その時濃厚な時間を過ごさせていただいたんだよね。
We spent some very intense time together then, didn't we?
楽しかった～、楽しかった～
It was so much fun!
二人のASMRボイス販売中なのでよろしくお願いします。
Their ASMR voices are currently on sale, so check them out!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
何だか恥ずかしい～
It's a bit embarrassing~
でも今日はパトラの誕生日だから
But since it's my birthday today...
何か二人からご褒美がもらえるって聞いたんだけど
I heard I could get a reward from you two!
パトラ様のご褒美？
A reward for Patra-sama?
FUWAMOCOは聞いてないです！
FUWAMOCO hasn't heard about this!
そんなそんな、ほら、パトラ
No, no, come on. It's my...
せっかくの誕生日だしね、はい。
...special birthday, after all!
いや、ご褒美どうしよう。
Hmm, what should the reward be?
ハグとか。
Maybe a hug?
え、ハグ？
Eh? A hug?
パトラ、ハグおねがいします！
Patra, please give us a hug!
はい、もうどこでも触って下さい、ありがとうございます。
Yes! You can touch me anywhere. Thank you!
角のはずです、じゃあ。せーの。
It's supposed to be the horns. Ready? One, two!
ハッピーバースデー！ハグ！バウバウ！
Happy Birthday! Hug! Bau bau!
幸せ～。フワワの方がなんかムニムニしてる。
So happy~ Fuwawa feels kind of squishy.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much!
おっとっと、ちょっと待って、モコちゃん、モコちゃん！
Whoops! Wait, Moco-chan, Moco-chan!
モコちゃ～ん。
Moco-cha~n!
いや、そこは可愛いんだけどね、モコちゃんはね、モコちゃん。
That part's cute, but Moco-chan is, well...
妹なんだから。
...the younger sister, after all.
はぁ～、可愛い、可愛い。
Haa~ So cute, so cute!
可愛い、プルプルプルプルプルプル...可愛い、頑張ってる可愛い。
Cute! *Wiggle wiggle* So cute! She's doing her best!
ご褒美だ。
This is a real reward.
今日はね、三人でまたね、歌が歌えると。
Today, the three of us get to sing together again!
イェ～イ！
Yay!
あ、じゃ、ちょっとパト露出が激しいので着ますね。ホイ！
Since I'm showing too much skin, let me change. Hoi!
あ～、可愛い！ありがとう～！
Ah! So cute! Thank you!
じゃ、早速いきます。はい。
Let's get right to it!
それでは聴いて下さい。「さくらんぼキッス」！
Please listen: "Sakuranbo Kiss"!
あげれおかしなこのドキドキは
This strange pounding in my heart...
君の腕の中で溢れ出す
...is overflowing in your arms.
ぽろり零れた涙さくらんぼ
A single tear falls, like a cherry.
もっとぎゅっとずっとしててね
Please hold me tight, forever.
好き好き好き...
Love, love, love...
まだまだかな君のハート
Is your heart still not ready?
ちょっと酸っぱい。本当？
It's a little sour. Really?
おやおやおや待ちきれない
Oh my, I just can't wait!
このままじゃ... ね、待って。
At this rate... hey, wait!
遠くのフリはやだよ
I don't like pretending to be far away
何気なくふわっと
Casually, lightly
隣り合わせて瞳近づく
Side by side, eyes getting closer
本当ね？
Really?
ずっと好きだったの 内緒だよ
I've always liked you, it's a secret
イェイ！
Yay!
あれれ小さな胸が震えてる
Oh my, my small heart is trembling
抱きしめられたら壊れちゃうよ
I'd break if you hugged me
夢で見ていたのより切ないね
It's more painful than I dreamed
だからもっとそっとしてね
So please be gentler
ポロリ外れたから涙あふれちゃう
Tears overflow as they spill out
大人になるための痛みかな
Is this the pain of growing up?
君に触れられた頬染まってく
My cheeks turn red where you touched them
キスはちょっとだけ待ってね
Wait just a bit for a kiss
好き好き好き 好き好き好き 好き好き好き 好き好き好き
Love love love, love love love, love love love, love love love
ハイハイ！
Alright, alright!
好き好き好き 好き好き好き 好き好き好き 好き好き好き
Love love love, love love love, love love love, love love love
キュンキュン！
Kyun kyun!
やだやだやだよ余所見は嫌だ
No no no, I don't like you looking elsewhere
もっとギュッとしていて
Hug me tighter
ポンポン！
Pon pon!
はなはなはなればなれもまだ子供だもんだも
Even being apart is still for children
だもん！
I said so!
君の余裕がグサッと
Your composure stabs
胸の奥に刺さるよ
Deep into my chest
この私スパッと忘れさせてね
Make me forget everything
優しいキスで
With a gentle kiss
なんだかなぁ...
I don't know...
ギュッとしちゃうよ
I'll hug you
内緒だよ
It's a secret
イェイ！
Yay!
あれれ唇があふれている
Oh my, lips are overflowing
君のまつげが瞳に映る
Your eyelashes are reflected in my eyes
鼓動波打つ速さ急上昇
The speed of my heartbeat is skyrocketing
だけどちょっとかなり幸せ
But I'm actually quite happy
小鳥時にも止まる瞬間に
In the moment when even little birds stop
壊れそうな心溶けだす
My fragile heart begins to melt
赤くはじけた私さくらんぼ
I'm a bright red cherry that's popped open
君とずっと繋がってたい
I want to be connected with you forever
神様、この唇は彼と出会うために生まれてきたのですね
God, these lips were born just to meet him, weren't they?
すました顔で決めて
Striking a pose with a serious face
遠くのフリはやだよ
I don't like pretending to be far away
何気なくふわっと
Casually, lightly
隣り合わせて瞳近づく
Side by side, eyes getting closer
だってね、こんなの初めてなの 内緒だよ
Because, this is the first time for me, it's a secret
やったー！
I did it!
あれれおかしなこのドキドキは
Oh my, this strange heart-pounding
君の腕の中であふれだす
Overflows in your arms
ポロリこぼれた涙さくらんぼ
Tears spill out like cherries
もっとギュッとずっとしてて
Keep hugging me tighter and tighter
あれれ世界がくるり回りだす
Oh my, the world starts spinning around
ふわふわ夢見心地風任せ
A fluffy dreamlike feeling, leaving it to the wind
ずっと待ってた恋は止まらない
The love I've been waiting for won't stop
だからずっと離さないで
So never let me go
好き好き好き 好き好き好き 好き好き好き 好き好き好き
Love love love, love love love, love love love, love love love
ハイハイ！
Alright, alright!
好き好き好き 好き好き好き 好き好き好き 好き好き好き
Love love love, love love love, love love love, love love love
キュンキュン！
Kyun kyun!
ワンワン！
Bow wow!
みんな！ 周防パトラ生誕祭、盛り上げてくれてどうもありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for livening up the Suou Patra Birthday Party!
まだまだ歌っちゃうから、盛り上げよろしくお願いします！
I'm going to keep singing, so please keep the energy up!
偉大なる悪魔は実は大天使パトラちゃん様なのだー！
The Great Devil is actually the Archangel Patra-chan-sama!
びっくびっくびっくびっくお邪魔様
Ex-ex-ex-excuse me
いっぱい食べて褒めて甘やかしてよ
Eat a lot, praise me, and spoil me
転んでひゅうと泣かせないで
Don't fall and make me cry
戦わないモンスターに負けないで
Don't lose to monsters that don't fight
ひるの運命は自分で切り開け
Carve out your own destiny during the day
バカというほうがバカ
The one who calls others an idiot is the idiot
超セクシーでキュートで断然プリティーが基本です
Super sexy, cute, and definitely pretty is the basics
文化的最低限のボニボニ It's my life
Culturally minimum boniboni, it's my life
むにむにむにむに頬むにょ
Squishy squishy squishy squishy, squishy cheeks
そもそもこんなに可愛いのに いつから悪魔と錯覚していた？
In the first place, I'm this cute, since when did you have the illusion that I'm a devil?
そうだそうだ！ 誤解およしな天使のような女の子
That's right, that's right! Stop the misunderstanding, I'm an angel-like girl
右に迷ったんじゃない
It's not that I got lost to the right
地球が逆回転したんじゃない
It's not that the Earth spun backwards
いつ、いづ、いづも、いつでもバトっていづも主役！
Always, always, always, always battling, I'm always the protagonist!
はぁー、なんだか疲れちゃった
Sigh, I'm kind of tired
時代が追いつくまで待とうかな
Maybe I'll wait until the era catches up
今日も誕生日！
Today is also my birthday!
ゼン！ゼン！ゼン！ゼン！
Zen! Zen! Zen! Zen!
ゼンキョーコメディ！
Zenkyo Comedy!
ゼンシンショーです！
It's a total show!
良いわなんだって
Everything's fine
今こそ一致団結
Unite together now
パトラちゃん様に
To Lady Patra...
愛を込めてー！
...with all your love!
パトラちゃん様ー！
Lady Patra!
イッツゼエライマーイ
It's the elai my life
生きてりゃこんくらい語り種さ
As long as you're alive, this is just a story to tell
それで？
And?
だって！
But!
大変楽しい方で良いでしょう？
Isn't it better to be very happy?
イッツゼエライマーイ
It's the elai my life
生きてりゃコツメて甘やかしな
If you're alive, live frugally and pamper yourself
今日転んで尻餅つかないで
Don't fall and land on your butt today
戦え！
Fight!
どんなモンスターにも負けないで
Don't lose to any monster
自分の運命は
Your destiny is...
自分できりひらけー！
...yours to carve out!
バカと言う方がバカ！
The one who calls others a fool is the fool!
セクシーでキュートで
Sexy and cute,
タイニーでプリティーな
tiny and pretty,
健康で文化的な最低限の
healthy, cultural and minimum
ボインボイン
boin boin!
イッツマイライフ！
It's my life!
むにむにむにむにハピムニュ
Muni muni muni muni Happy munyu
みんなー！コメントでお祝いどうもありがとー！
Everyone! Thanks so much for the celebratory comments!
見えてるよー！
I can see them!
お！パトラちゃん可愛いって打ってる？
Oh! Are you typing that Patra-chan is cute?
ちょっと！そこの君、サボってんじゃないよ！
Hey! You over there, don't slack off!
画面の向こう見えてるぞー！
I can see you behind the screen!
さあさあ、たくさんコメント打っていい！
Come on, go ahead and type lots of comments!
笑われちまっても気にすんな
Don't mind if you're laughed at
そのまま終わるより素晴らしいと誇れ
Take pride that it's more wonderful than just ending like that
別れの約束を忘れるな
Don't forget the promise of parting
カッコ悪く生きろ
Live uncoolly
傷ついた思い出に
Against the painful memories,
負けない自分になり！
become someone who won't lose!
みんなー！盛り上げてくれてどうもありがとー！
Everyone! Thank you so much for hyping things up!
この後は一緒に、パトラちゃん様と言ってください！
After this, please say 'Lady Patra-chan' with me!
せーの！
Ready, go!
パトラちゃん様ー！
Lady Patra-chan!
どうもありがとー！
Thank you so much!
イッツゼエライマーイ
It's the elai my life
生きてりゃこんくらい語り種さ
As long as you're alive, this is just a story to tell
それで？
And?
だって！
But!
大変楽しい方で良いでしょう？
Isn't it better to be very happy?
イッツゼエライマーイ
It's the elai my life
生きてりゃハメ外して甘やかしな
If you're alive, let loose and pamper yourself
今日転んで尻餅つかないで
Don't fall and land on your butt today
戦え！
Fight!
どんなモンスターにも負けないで
Don't lose to any monster
自分の運命は
Your destiny is...
自分できりひらけー！
...yours to carve out!
バカと言う方がバカ！
The one who calls others a fool is the fool!
セクシーでキュートで
Sexy and cute,
タイニーでプリティーな
tiny and pretty,
健康で文化的な最低限の
healthy, cultural and minimum
ボインボイン
boin boin!
イッツマイライフ！
It's my life!
むにむにむにむにハピムニュ
Muni muni muni muni Happy munyu
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
もう一回！
One more time!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
移動してるよ！ちょっと待ってね！
I'm moving! Please wait a moment!
はい！
Hai!
みなさーん、パトララインでーす！
Everyone, it's the Patra-Line!
まだまだ後半戦、盛り上げていってくださいねー！
The second half is just starting, please keep up the hype!
静かなこの夜に あなたを待ってるの
In this quiet night, I'm waiting for you
あの時忘れた 微笑みを取りに来て
Come to retrieve the smile you forgot back then
あれから少しだけ 時間が過ぎて
Since then, a little time has passed
想い出が優しくなったね
And the memories have become gentle
星の降る場所で あなたが笑っていることを
In the place where stars fall, that you are smiling...
いつも願ってた 今遠くても
...is what I always wished for, even if we're far apart now
また逢えるよね
We can meet again, right?
はい！
Hai!
いつかの微笑みは こんなに儚くて
That smile from before is so fleeting
一つの間違いで 壊れてしまうから
Because it could break with just one mistake
大切なものだけを 光に変えて
Changing only the important things into light
遠い空 越えて行く強さだけ
Only the strength to cross the distant sky
星のふる場所へ
To the place where stars fall
想いをあなたに届けたい
I want to deliver my feelings to you
いつもそばにいる
Always by your side
We are in the Quiet Night
独りじゃない
Not alone
歌うから生誕祭があるのではありません
It's not that there's a birthday party because I sing
生誕祭があるから歌うので
It's because there's a birthday party that I sing
星のふる場所で
At the place where stars fall
あなたが笑っていることを
That you are laughing
いつも願ってた
I always wished for
今は遠くても
Even if we're far apart now
また逢えるよね
We'll meet again, right?
星のふる場所へ
To the place where stars fall
想いをあなたに届けたい
I want to deliver my feelings to you
いつもそばにいる
Always by your side
We are in the Quiet Night
独りじゃない
Not alone
いっぱい聞いてくれてどうもありがとう！
Thank you so much for listening!
それでは次はお待ちかねのビデオレターです！
And now, the long-awaited video letters!
どうぞ！
Please enjoy!
周防パトラお姉ちゃん、
Big sister Suou Patra,
お誕生日おめでとうございます！わーい！パチパチパチ。
Happy Birthday! Yay! *claps*
バーチャルYouTuberの可憐です。
I'm Virtual YouTuber Karen.
パトラお姉ちゃんは何度も可憐の番組に出てくれたりして、
Patra-oneechan has appeared on my show many times,
可憐、とってもとっても感謝しています。
I am very, very grateful.
最近だと、去年の12月20日の生放送かな？
Recently, was it the live stream on December 20th last year?
に、ゲストとして来てくれました。
You came as a guest.
可憐それまでちょっとコールドスリープでお休みしてたんで、
I had been on a break in cold sleep until then,
まさかまたね、パトラお姉ちゃんが可憐の番組に来て再会できると思ってなかったので、
so I never thought I'd meet Patra-oneechan on my show again,
もうすっごくすっごく嬉しかったんです。
I was so, so happy.
その時はパピプペポゲームで盛り上がったりしてましたけど、
At that time, we had a lot of fun with the Papipupepo game,
皆さん見てくれたかな？
Did everyone see it?
あ、もし見てくれてない方、アーカイブ残ってます。
Ah, if you haven't seen it, the archive is still there.
はい。そんなパトラお姉ちゃんには可憐のあのソロ曲、
Yes. For such a Patra-oneechan, my solo song,
「ラブメロディ」もパトラお姉ちゃんに作っていただいて。
you also composed "Love Melody" for me.
可憐ね、いつかパトラお姉ちゃんと一緒にその曲を、
I have a dream of one day singing that song together with Patra-oneechan,
何だろう、デュエットって言うのかな？一緒に歌えたらいいなっていう夢を持っています。
as a duet, I suppose? I hope we can sing it together.
その夢が叶うように、可憐もこれからも頑張りたいと思います。
I'll do my best from now on so that the dream comes true.
パトラお姉ちゃんもいつまでも体には気をつけて頑張ってください。
Patra-oneechan, please take care of yourself and keep doing your best.
では、これからの1年もパトラお姉ちゃんにとって素敵な素敵な1年になりますように。
Well then, I hope this coming year is a wonderful, wonderful one for you.
パトラお姉ちゃん、大好き！
Patra-oneechan, I love you!
おやすみなさい。
Good night.
パトラちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Patra-chan, Happy Birthday!
漫画家・イラストレーターの飯田ぽち。と申します。
I'm manga artist and illustrator Iida Pochi.
このお仕事をしておりますと、時々身心ともにエネルギー切れになってね、疲れてしまうことも多いんですけれども。
Doing this job, I often run out of energy both mentally and physically and get tired.
そんな時にね、いつもパトラちゃんが「新作楽しみにしてます！」「読みました！」とか、あと「グッズ買いました！」と伝えてくださるので、
At those times, Patra-chan always tells me "I'm looking forward to your new work!", "I read it!", or "I bought your goods!"
いつも私、心の栄養をもらっております。
so I'm always getting mental nourishment.
パトラちゃんのおかげでいつも頑張れております。
Thanks to Patra-chan, I can always keep going.
いつもありがとう。
Thank you always.
そんなね、パトラちゃんの優しさに甘えてしまっていて、わたくし日頃お世話になりっぱなしですので、
I've been leaning on Patra-chan's kindness and always being taken care of,
そろそろね、わたくしからも何かお恩返しをさせてくださいね。
so soon, please let me do something to repay the favor.
いつでもね、なんかあったら気軽に声かけてください。
Feel free to reach out to me anytime if you need anything.
というわけで、パトラちゃんのますますのご活躍と、そして今年がね、素敵な一年になること、心から願っております。
Anyway, I sincerely wish for Patra-chan's continued success and for this year to be a wonderful one.
改めて本日はお誕生日おめでとうございます。
Congratulations on your birthday today once again.
飯田ぽち。でした。
This was Iida Pochi.
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
パトラちゃん！ハッピーバースデー！お誕生日おめでとう！
Patra-chan! Happy Birthday! Congratulations on your birthday!
にじさんじ所属の...
I am a member of Nijisanji...
やっほー、夜夢レナです！
Hi, I'm Yomemi Lena!
パトちゃんとはね、なんだかんだつるんで、まぁASMR絡みが、多いですけど
I hang out with Patra-chan for various reasons, mostly involving ASMR...
実は、夜夢、パトちゃんと、ゲームも一緒にしたいなー、って思ってるんだよね
But actually, I want to play games with you too, Patra-chan!
なので、今度一緒にゲームで遊んでくださーい！
So, please play games with me next time!
またね、いつメンでご飯も行こうね！
Let's also go grab food with the usual gang again!
もちろん、夜夢と二人きりでも、いいですけどね
Of course, just the two of us would be fine too!
パトちゃんにとって素敵な一日を過ごしてね
Hope you have a wonderful day, Patra-chan!
ほな、またね。連絡待ってまーす。バイバーイ！
Well, see ya! I'll be waiting for your message! Bye-bye!
パトラ、お誕生日おめでとう！
Patra, happy birthday!
太古の女が、また1秒1秒とこのように存在を刻んでいるね
The ancient woman is once again carving her existence second by second.
このまま永遠に刻んでいってくれよな
Keep carving it like this forever.
突然私事なんですけれども、最近生活リズムが終わってるんですよね
On a personal note, my daily rhythm has been a total mess recently.
今に始まったことじゃないんですけど
It's nothing new, though.
そこで、私はパトラの「おはよう配信」から始まって、「ASMRおやすみ配信」で終わるパトラ24が欲しいと思っているんです
So, I want a "Patra 24" that starts with your morning stream and ends with your ASMR night stream.
パトラ、1日生活動画が欲しい！
Patra, I want a "day in the life" video!
パトラで、俺の生活を整えたい！
I want to fix my life with Patra!
どうですか？
How about it?
お誕生日、おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
パトラ、誕生日おめでとうー！
Patra, happy birthday!
いやー誕生日ですか、めでたいですねー
Wow, it's your birthday. That's a celebratory occasion.
またね、プレゼント渡しに家行くんだよね。ぜひぜひ入れてください
I'll be going to your house again to give you a present. Please let me in.
また行くからね、お家。ダラダラしに行くからね。グッズも持っていくからね
I'm coming over to lounge around again. I'll bring some goods too.
おめでとう！またねー！
Congratulations! See you later!
やービデオレターありがとうございましたー！
Wow, thank you so much for the video letters!
本当にね、いろんな子たちからのビデオレターありがたいです。家宝にします！ありがとうございました！
I'm so grateful for all the letters. I'll cherish them! Thank you!
それではですね、次は告知になります！どうぞ！
And now, it's time for some announcements! Here you go!
皆さん、こんにちはわん。周防パトラです
Hello everyone. I'm Suou Patra.
パトダイレクトをご覧いただきありがとうございます
Thank you for watching Pato Direct.
今日は全部で4つの告知があります
I have four announcements in total today.
それではまず、こちらの告知をご覧ください
First, please take a look at this announcement.
メタル・ラブ・メソッド
Metal Love Method
GITADORA GALAXY WAVE DELTAに楽曲収録！
Song included in GITADORA GALAXY WAVE DELTA!
このあとLIVE後すぐにあそべます♡
You can play it immediately after the stream ends♡
この度、アミューズメント施設向けの音楽ゲーム「GITADORA」シリーズのアリーナモデル筐体にて、楽曲収録することになりました！
My song will be included in the "GITADORA" series' Arena Model cabinets!
なんと曲はメタル！BEMANI Sound Team あさきさんとダブルギター！
It's a metal track with a double guitar part by Asaki-san from BEMANI Sound Team!
このライブが終わった後、ゲーム内で誰でもプレイできるようになります！
After this stream, anyone will be able to play it in the game!
ゲーム内の「GALAXY WAVE DELTA」カテゴリーから選曲してみてね！
Look for it under the "GALAXY WAVE DELTA" category!
初めてギタドラをプレイするよという人は、ルーキーモードでぜひプレイしてみてください
If it's your first time playing, please try it in Rookie Mode.
また、19時からコナミ公式YouTubeチャンネルから、この楽曲のフルバージョンもアップ予定！
The full version will also be uploaded to the official Konami channel at 7:00 PM!
皆さん、ぜひギタドラで遊んでみてね！
Everyone, please give GITADORA a try!
やったー！ついに発表！
Hooray! Finally announcing it!
周防パトラフィギュア第2弾が登場しちゃいます！
The second Suou Patra figure is coming soon!
今回のテーマは、ASMR配信の世界観を詰め込んだ、周防パトラ監修の完全オリジナルポーズ！
The theme is a unique pose supervised by me, capturing the world of ASMR streams!
髪の毛は透明パーツで毛先まで美しく。
The hair uses transparent parts for a beautiful finish to the tips.
お洋服の艶感、チョーカーやベルトの金具まで忠実に再現。
The gloss of the clothes and metal fittings are faithfully reproduced.
おへそ周りのシースルーは、はぁ...ため息もの...
The see-through area around the navel is... *sigh*... breathtaking...
お尻、胸、足裏まで、職人技で丁寧に仕上げました。
Crafted with care, from the chest to the soles of the feet.
耳かきやクッション、ラグマットも超可愛い！
The ear pick, cushion, and rug are also super cute!
クッションにはパトラのサイン入りだよ。
The cushion even features Patra's signature.
そして、気分で楽しめる表情差し替えパーツ付き！
It also comes with interchangeable parts for different expressions!
ちょっと困り顔も楽しんでね！
Please enjoy the slightly troubled expression too!
25日から開始です。
Starts on the 25th.
予約締め切りは10月17日までだよ。
The reservation deadline is October 17th.
絶対ゲットしてね！
Make sure to get it!
はあ、パトラちゃん、お腹が空いて力が出ないよ。
Sigh, Patra-chan, I'm so hungry I have no energy.
そんな時はこれ！
In times like this, take this!
手作り風うめーパトラのカニカマカレー！
Homemade-style UMEE Patra's Kanikama Curry!
ピリッとスパイスの効いたカレーに、
A spicy curry with...
カニカマがゴロゴロ。うめー！
...chunks of imitation crab meat. So good!
グラシャス！
Gracious!
ギリギリOKだね。
Just barely made it.
ついに出た！周防パトラ全面監修、
It's finally here! Fully supervised by Suou Patra,
手作り風うめーパトラのカニカマカレー！
homemade-style UMEE Patra's Kanikama Curry!
2025年10月1日発売！
On sale October 1st, 2025!
1箱に2食入り。
Two servings per box.
パトラのオリジナルカードが全6種類、1枚入りだよ。
Includes one of six original Patra cards.
そしてなんと、パトラのうめー皿＆
And what's more, the UMEE plate &
パトラのうまいスプーンセット発売だよ。
Umai spoon set is also on sale.
スプーンはパトラがイラストを書いたよ。
I drew the illustrations for the spoon.
栄養満点！パトラの愛情も満点だよ。
Full of nutrition! Full of Patra's love, too.
詳細はまたXなどでお知らせするね。
I'll announce the details later on X and others.
楽しみにしててね！
Look forward to it!
全部で3つの告知をご覧いただきありがとうございます。
Thank you for watching all three announcements.
ギタドラ、カレー、それからフリューさんでは第2弾のフィギュアが出ることになりました。
Gitadora, curry, and a second figure from FuRyu.
楽しみですね！
How exciting!
それでは次に最後の告知です。
And now, the final announcement.
ご覧ください。
Please take a look.
周防パトラ……？
Suou Patra...?
って、だれ？
...who is that?
記憶をなくしたパトラと君が織りなす、もしもの物語。
A story of "what if" woven by you and a Patra who has lost her memories.
『君色パトライフ』ゲーム制作決定！
Game production for "Kimiiro Patra IF" confirmed!
パトラのこと、拾ってくれますか？
Will you pick me up?
はい！ということで盛りだくさんの告知でした！
All right! So, those were a lot of announcements!
みんなびっくりした？
Was everyone surprised?
後でね、Xの方にも情報出しますので、よろしくお願いします。
I'll post the info on X later, so please check it out.
そしてね、ここまでたくさん歌ったんですけど、次でラストの曲になります。
I've sung a lot until now, but the next one will be the last song.
おおー、コメントもたくさんありがとうございます。
Oh, thank you so much for all the comments.
じゃあね、今年もこうしてね、新3Dが出せたり、
The reason I was able to release a new 3D model
あの、素敵なステージでライブができたのは、応援してくれてるみんなのおかげです。
and perform on such a stage is thanks to everyone's support.
今日もね、ハッシュタグでたくさん呟いてくれてどうもありがとう！
Thank you for all your tweets with the hashtag today, too!
そしてそして、本日のステージを作ってくださいました、Brave Groupの皆さん、本当にありがとうございました！
And also, a huge thank you to everyone at Brave Group who created today's stage!
すごいんだよね。パトラがね、あの、パン…言っちゃった、
It's amazing. Since I tend to show what's under my...
あの、スカートの中、よく見せちゃうので、
...skirt often,
今日ね、素敵なアングルを考えて取ってくれました。本当にありがとうございました！
they captured wonderful angles for me today. Thank you so much!
はい！それでは、次の曲、なんと新曲になります！
Yes! Now, the next song is actually a new song!
ぜひ聴いてください。
Please listen to it.
新曲は、『みんな〜！』
The new song is "Everyone~!"
みん、みん、みん、みんな〜！
Min, min, min, Everyone~!
君は噛めば噛むほど味が出るもの知ってる？
Do you know what gets better the more you chew it?
人類の常識を越えて、デキソコナイなもの、教えてあげるね。
Beyond common sense, I'll teach you about something half-baked.
みんな、みんな、みんな、みんな、ゲームするよ！
Everyone, everyone, everyone, everyone, let's play a game!
みんな、みんな、みんな、みんな、みんな、みんな、古今東西！
Everyone, everyone, everyone, everyone, everyone, everyone, Kokon Tozai!
気がついたら24時間ゲームばかりしてる。
Before I knew it, I was playing games for 24 hours straight.
現実幻夢の中、どういうわけかやめられない。
In a dream of reality, for some reason I can't stop.
時限まりデバフを引いて最初からやり直し。
Triggered a time-limit debuff and starting over from the beginning.
爆笑！闇の中、それでもずっとやめられない。
Laughing! In the darkness, I still can't stop.
昔の昔の黒歴史。絶対誰でもあるよ、あるよ。
An old, old dark past. Everyone definitely has one.
デバッグちゃんどうしたのかな。なんて楽しんだもの勝ち！救え未来！
What happened to Debug-chan? The one who enjoys it wins! Save the future!
あの一生懸命には意味がある。パトは三倍。パトは三倍増す。
There's meaning in that hard work. Pato is three times as much.
みんな踊れ！みんな叫べ！爆音でブリッジした！
Everyone dance! Everyone scream! Bridged with explosive sound!
けれどもクソゲーなんて
But there are no shitty games...
この世にない
...in this world.
クリアして笑ってやるんだ
I'll clear them and laugh.
みんな笑え みんな踊れ
Everyone laugh, everyone dance!
一吐息も我慢してるんだろう
You're holding your breath, aren't you?
ダサいのにね 羨ましい
It's lame, but I'm jealous.
そんな風に生きてみたいな
I want to live like that too.
気がついたらみんなみんな手呼びかけたりしてる
When I noticed, I was calling out to everyone.
神ゲー レアゲー 行くぜ 好奇心は止められない
God-tier game, rare game, let's go! Can't stop the curiosity.
良いことも悪いことも 君の人生の味方になれ
Good or bad, I'll be an ally in your life.
みんな踊れ みんな叫べ
Everyone dance, everyone shout!
ゲームオーバーまたリトライすればいい
Game over? Just retry again!
諦められない ここで
I can't give up here.
ハッピーエンドにこそみんな笑え
Everyone laugh at the happy end!
みんな踊れ 夢だけが
Everyone dance, so your dreams...
綺麗事じゃないように
...won't be just lip service.
甘い約束 エトセトラ 悲しい時には泣けばいいんだよ
Sweet promises and so on, it's okay to cry when you're sad.
なんでそんなに難しい顔してるんですか？
Why are you making such a difficult face?
まあ ゴールしてもいいかな？
Well, is it okay if I goal already?
いやいや 思いを込めたもの全てを見届けたい
No, no, I want to see everything I put my heart into through to the end.
そんな行方が見たいだけ
I just want to see how it turns out.
みんなみんな不安なんだ 世の中にね
Everyone, everyone is anxious in this world.
自分のこと許してくれる人がいるのかな
I wonder if there's someone who will forgive me.
挑戦したら勇者
If you take the challenge, you're a hero.
みんな踊れ みんな叫べ
Everyone dance, everyone shout!
知らないこと無理したけれども
I tried hard even though I didn't know.
クソゲーなんてこの世にない
There are no shitty games in this world.
クリアして見せて笑ってやるんだ
I'll show you I can clear it and laugh.
おーい、お疲れ様でしたー！
Phew, good job everyone!
ね、カニカマもいてくれたの？
Hey, were the Kanikama here too?
どうもお疲れ様でした
Thank you very much, good job.
いや今日はね、あ、みんな！みんな！みんな！終わってたよ
So today... ah, everyone! It's over!
今日はね、あの、なんと前回と同じステージと思いつつ
Today, while it might look like the same stage as last time...
ちょっとね、変化があるんですよ
...there are actually some changes!
ステージの紹介をしたいなーって思います
I'd like to introduce the stage details.
まだまだあるよ
There's still more.
見て見て見て見てこれ
Look, look, look at this!
なんと前回よりもプレゼントが増えています！ダダーン！
There are even more presents than last time! Ta-da!
ほらほら何が入っているのかなーっていうね形になってるのと
See? It's like "I wonder what's inside?"
あとここ！カニカマがちょっと変化してます 分かるでしょうか？
And here! The Kanikama have changed a bit. Can you tell?
えー、最低の間違い探しじゃないですけど
Well, it's not like a high-level "spot the difference," but...
微っ妙に変わっております
...they have changed slightly.
なんとカニカマが増えています！
Surprisingly, the number of Kanikama has increased!
気づいた？気づいたかな？
Did you notice? I wonder if you did.
あとステージ全体はこうなってまーす！
And here's the entire stage!
おおー豪華！
Ooh, so luxurious!
すごいよね、キラキラ度も増しております
It's amazing, isn't it? The sparkle level has also increased.
みんなも応援ありがとう！
Thank you all for the support!
それからね、でーっかいサムネイル、可愛い！
And look at this huge thumbnail, so cute!
同じ同じポ、ポ、なんか違うような気がするけど…あ、同じポーズ！
The same po-pose... I feel like it's a bit different, but... ah, same pose!
ね、すごい豪華に描いてもらえました
Right? I had it drawn so luxuriously.
それから、あ！はい！シロパトー！
And also, ah! Yes! Shiropato!
はいはいはい、今日のね、はい、あまりね出番がなかったシロパトちゃんです！
Yes, yes! This is Shiropato, who didn't get much screen time today!
ね、今日はね1曲目ね歌ってくれてどうもありがとうねシロパト
Hey, thank you for singing the first song today, Shiropato.
みんなは白と黒どっちのパトラが好き？
Do you guys like white or black Patra better?
お！あ、ね、シロパトちゃんの方がちょっとね柔らかいの ほら跳ねて跳ねて
Oh! Shiropato is a bit softer, see? Boing, boing!
そうのなの、やっぱパトはね鉄製のねベルトが巻いてあるからね
That's right, because black Pato has a steel belt wrapped around her.
シロパトちゃんの方が柔らかいんですよ
Shiropato is definitely softer.
ほらほらよく見て見て二人のツーショット
Look closely at this two-shot of us.
みんなどっちが好きかな？どっちも好き？
I wonder which one you like? Or do you like both?
あ、ありがとうございます！あ、じゃあ高評価チャンネル登録もぜひよろしくお願いしまーす！
Ah, thank you! Please remember to like and subscribe!
みんな本当に今日はありがとう！これからもよろしくね！バイバイ！
Thank you all so much for today! See you next time! Bye-bye!
生誕祭ライブ終わりました！
The birthday festival live is over!
つたない歌と豪華なステージで はしゃぐパトが今年もできたのは あなたのおかげです。
The reason Pato was able to have fun with my unpolished singing and a luxurious stage this year too is thanks to you.
今日もこの世界に生きててくれてありがとう！パトは今皆といることが一番楽しいです。
Thank you for living in this world today too! Pato is happiest being with everyone right now.
それはきっと世界で一番幸せなことです。
That is surely the happiest thing in the world.
生誕祭ライブ終わりました！
The birthday celebration live has ended!
つたない歌と豪華なステージで
With my clumsy singing and a gorgeous stage,
はしゃぐパトが今年もできたのは
the fact that Patra could frolic again this year
あなたのおかげです。
is all thanks to you.
今日もこの世界に生きててくれてありがとう！
Thank you for being alive in this world today!
パトは今皆といることが一番楽しいです。♡
Patra is having the most fun being with everyone right now. ♡
それはきっと世界で一番幸せなことです。
That is surely the happiest thing in the world.
周防パトラ
Suou Patra
周防パトラ 誕生3Dライブ 2025
3D新髪型お披露目 GUEST FUWAMOCO
Suou Patra Birthday 3D Live 2025
3D New Hairstyle Reveal - GUEST: FUWAMOCO